(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-18T22:24:42.363619",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Attention please, Motherfeathers!
Today, I've got some amazing guests here to celebrate my birthday with me!
Everyone, come on out!
Woohoo! Yay!
Happy birthday!
Happy birthday, Reine!
Yay! Wow, nice place.
It's like we're in Indonesia!
We are in Indonesia!
I'm ready for a vacation, baby!
We finally made that Indonesian vacation!
Anyways, we have Calliope!
Oh, hi guys! はーい、みなさん、It's me Mori Calliope from hololive English -Myth-!
Oh, hi guys! Hi everyone, it's me Mori Calliope from hololive English -Myth-!
What's going on? 破滅はここです、です。Let's have fun together! やった！
What's going on? Destruction is here! Let's have fun together! Yay!
We have Takanashi Kiara!
Yes! Kikiriki, I am also from hololive English -Myth-!
I am Takanashi Kiara, and finally, finally I made it to Indonesia again!
My second time! Yay!
And we have Zeta!
Hi! Finally I'm back in Indonesia!
Back in Indonesia! Aw, cute cat! Aw, what a cute cat!
Did you bring some Churu? Churu? You have Churu? You want treat?
No! No!
She hates that.
Is this your new cat? / This is my new house cat, you like her?
Aw, so cute! Okay.
For this year's birthday, I've put together lots of fun activities!
So I went on location shoots in both Indonesia and Japan!
And I'm also playing games that are popular in Indonesia with these wonderful guests!
Yay!
And guess what? I'll be performing a brand-new song at the end of the stream!
So don't miss it, and stay until the very end!
Yes, don't leave! Don't leave. Listen to her, or else! Yes, or else.
The peafowl is talking, listen to her!
So first, let's take a look at the video from my location shoot in Indonesia.
Let's go! Take it!
Attention please! I'm Pavolia Reine, reporting from BSD City, Indonesia.
I've talked a lot about spicy food in Indonesia, but...
...today, I will be introducing a wider variety of Indonesian food for everyone to get to know it even better!
Can anybody guess what we'll be eating today?
Here we are at Jalarasa The Breeze, BSD!
Embark on a culinary journey through the enchanting flavors of Indonesia at Jalarasa Indonesian Cuisine.
We are proud to bring you the authentic tastes of this archipelago nation.
Join us and celebrate Indonesia's culinary tapestry!
First, we have perkedel jagung.
Perkedel jagung are sweet corn fritters served with sambal roa.
Mmm, you know how much I talk about this sambal.
Indonesia has a wide variety of sambal from different regions.
Sambal roa is a Manado specialty, and it is made mainly from chilies...
...and smoked ballyhoo fish.
Mari kita coba.
Let's give it a try.
Enak... Yummy!
Delicious... Yummy!
Next we're going to take some tahu lada garam.
Mmm, salt and pepper tofu, yummy!
Ooh, it's salt-pepper fried tofu complete with Indonesian aromatics.
Let's have a taste!
Hmm, this is like buttery flavor, I like it so much.
Hmm, this is like a buttery flavor, I like it so much.
And this one is a Sundanese specialty called karedok.
It's a traditional salad that uses a rich peanut sauce.
Mmm, it has green eggplants, cucumbers, lemon basil, long beans, as well as bean sprouts.
So fresh!
Seger banget.
Super refreshing.
Next up, we're going to go eat some fish!
This is also my first time eating this fish or even looking at this fish.
Did you guys know that a fish called Kudu-Kudu existed?
This is Kudu-Kudu telur asin...
Mmm, ini...
Mmm, this...
So like Indonesia really has such a rich cultural cuisine.
I've never even eaten this before.
This is one of Jala Rasa specialties.
This is one of Jala Rasa's specialties.
Haha, even the skin is so tough.
So this a boxfish apparently.
So this is a boxfish apparently.
This boxfish is served with a super popular telur asin sauce.
This boxfish is served with a super popular salted egg sauce.
The texture is membal-membal, you know.
The texture is bouncy and chewy, you know.
Enak banget!
It's so delicious!
I would recommend you guys eat this deh.
I would recommend you guys eat this.
Yeah, I get what they're saying. Yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah.
Yeah, I get what they're saying. Yeah, yeah, yeah...
Yeah, it tastes a little bit like chicken, it's so unique.
You guys definitely need to try it. Even like Indo bros, you guys go and try this.
Okay, so this is Iga Sapi Bakar Cabe Ijo.
Okay, so this is grilled beef ribs with green chili.
It's a Javanese specialty,
smoked rib served with sambal ijo, a.k.a green chili.
So unlike the previous sambal we had,
this one's made of only green chilis and other aromatics.
So the iga itself is sweet,
So the rib itself is sweet,
so combined with this spicy and a little bit savory
sambel ijo condiment, it makes for a really good dish.
green chili condiment, it makes for a really good dish.
Mmm.
Ih, dagingnya empuk juga.
Ooh, the meat is tender too.
The meat is so soft, I like I recommend this one.
The meat is so soft, I recommend this one.
And this one's a classic! You know what it is.
It's the beloved Nasi Goreng!
It's the beloved fried rice!
So we have this traditional chicken nasi goreng that's cooked with terasi ya, guys.
So we have this traditional chicken fried rice that's cooked with shrimp paste, you guys.
Terasi is a local shrimp or krill paste.
Mmm, smells so good.
Mmm, I think it's known as belacan in Malaysia and also kapi in Thailand, yeah.
Let's try this.
Mmm... It's a mix of sweet and...
spicy and savory! Mmm.
And as usual when you're eating Nasi Goreng, don't forget the kerupuk! Omn.
And as usual when you're eating fried rice, don't forget the crackers! Omn.
This is Nasi Liwet.
Nasi Liwet is a Sundanese specialty rice that is topped with
salted fish, fried shallots, and more salted fish.
Mmm, you can taste the depth of flavors.
Enak banget, sumpah ini gak bohong.
It's so delicious, I swear I'm not lying.
No lie lie, this is so good!
And this is a Jakarta specialty, Kangkung Hotplate!
Siapa yang suka makan kangkung di sini?
Who here likes eating water spinach?
So this morning glory is cooked with oyster sauce, and topped with quail eggs and shrimp!
Oh look at the shrimp, there's a lot of shrimp and seafood, mmm.
And this is Coto Makassar.
A Makassar specialty beef soup flavored with cloves and braised peanuts.
The history of Coto Makassar dates back to the 16th century during the era of the Gowa Kingdom.
Coto was a special dish that symbolized wealth and luxury, as it was said to be served only to kings and nobles.
Like me!!
Let's give it a taste.
Mmm... Yummy.
Cloves tuh itu lho guys, cengkeh, cengkeh.
Cloves is that thing, guys, cloves, cloves.
Mmm, so fresh, menyegarkan.
Mmm, so fresh, refreshing.
Now that we finished eating all the savory food, was really really good,
now it's time to close it with a dessert!
This time, we have Es Pisang Ijo.
Es Pisang Ijo literally means iced green bananas.
As you can see, look at these beautiful green bananas!
These bananas are wrapped in a green flour dough, and is served with coconut milk and pandan.
Let's give it a try!
Look at this, it also has sweet coconut rice pudding,
and Indonesian tapioca pearls with a beautiful pink color,
condensed milk, mmm, and a special Ambon Banana Syrup.
I really really like their coconut rice pudding.
Taste so good.
Tastes so good.
There's a little bit of savory complimenting the sweetness, mmm.
Wow, that was a crazy meal!
I can't believe the different flavor profile of every dish!
Mmm, from the jagung perkedel up until the dessert, mmm.
Mmm, from the corn fritters up until the dessert, mmm.
And the portions are pretty big, so if you guys come here, I recommend you to come with your friends and share.
That's why everybody, come visit Indonesia!
But in case
some of you are curious
but aren't ready to come to Indonesia...
Well, stay tuned for the next part coming up!
Hey, it's Reine back in the studio!
Did everyone enjoy our shoot in Indonesia?
The food was so delicious.
I really wish one day if you guys could go to Indonesia,
please have a try!
All right! Next up, we're gonna play our first game!
Yay!
We have to—shh! We have two games planned for today.
So let's move our bodies and have a blast together!
All right, let's get started.
Our first game is this!
Um, meow.
Sorry, sorry. There's a bit of distraction going on over here.
Oh god, sorry. There's a feral animal over here.
Yeah! Feral animal!
Guys, did you even notice this right here? What is this?
Everybody gather in! Gather around, gather around!
What is that? Apa sih?
What is that? What is it?
Apa sih? / What's that thing, Reine?
What is it? / What's that thing, Reine?
You gotta tell us what it is. Never seen anything like that in my life.
Okay, okay, okay. All right. Looks delicious though, right?
Totally don't know what that is. / I still don't know what it is.
Oh, maybe you know? / Apaan ya?
Oh, maybe you know? / What could it be?
Is it like senbei?
Is it like rice crackers?
Kinda, yeah. / Like a rice cake or something?
Tofu, tofu! / Tofu? / Tofu?
Okay, okay, okay. We'll—we'll explain.
So this one will be an individual competition.
It is not a team battle,
and everyone will be competing against each other. Got it?
Hey! Competition! / Okay.
So this one will be called the Royal Kerupuk Contest!
Kerupuk Contest! / Kerupuk! / Kerupuk!
Yeah, this is kerupuk, kerupuk, kerupuk. / Oh, that? / Yeah, crunchy crunchy.
Oh, what exactly is it? Is it like a food? / Yeah, it is. / Nice.
Yeah, you can totally eat it.
It's so pretty though, for being a food. / Yeah.
Yeah, so if you see, the start line is over there,
and then the line on this side is the turnaround line, so you go like ch-ch-ch-ch-ch and then shoo!
And then when the signal is given, you begin at the starting line, and you have to do five squats.
Eh?! Five?
I did five squats yesterday!
No, no, no, no, listen! / Only five? / The bright—the good thing is that there is no punishment game, okay?
'Cause this is the punishment. / This is the punishment game!
And then after you do five squats, you go run towards here,
and without using your hands, you jump and you just like grab it with your mouth,
and go nom nom nom nom nom.
After five squats? Oh, my legs are on fire.
And then whatever... you can finish it with your hands, yeah. And then when you're done, just be like, "Hey, I'm done!"
And then you run here,
and then you just shake your butt 10 times! I'll be watching!
10? Why 10? / Yeah. Oh, you want 20?
No, no, no, no, no! 10 is good, 10 is good.
20? Just say the word, Calli. / 10, no, 10 is perfect. / 10 is perfect? All right, good to know, good to know.
All right. So like you do 10, and then once we count and give the okay,
you run back, and then straight to the back, you know, the finish line, and then...
yeah, the fastest one this round wins, I guess.
Oh! / Okay! / Okay! / Yeah!
It'll be timed. Is this like... is this an Indonesian game?
Yeah, pretty much. It's a kerupuk eating contest, but I don't think you shake your butt. I just...
Oh, you don't shake your butt? / We gotta spice it in! Reine original move, okay?
Reine original move, okay. / It's an upgraded version!
Yeah! / Okay. Sure. Sounds good to me.
Okay. Well, there's a bit of a height difference, but it should be fine.
Oh, yeah! I think there's... I mean, we're all pretty tall except... / Except me!
Where are you going? / Where are you going?
This is kind of unfair. / We can measure our height there.
She just has to jump higher. Cats can jump pretty high normally. / That's a really good point.
I'm not a cat! / You are a cat!
You'll be fine. Secret agents are really good at jumping. / Okay, I'll jump. I'll jump really high. Okay.
Well, I guess so, you know, looking at our height, I guess me and Calli can go first?
Okay, okay! / Yay!
So Kiara and Zeta, you will be judging our hip shaking, so you can stand...
All right. / Ooh...
Kiara is gonna definitely give you more points though, because I feel like she definitely wants to see that. She wants to see you like throwing it back.
Well, I want to see you!
I can be pretty strict when it comes to butt shaking.
Maybe 'cause she wants to see more, she'll make you do twice as many.
Nah, nah, nah. / We'll see! / Gotta be fair.
20 for Mori Calliope? / Uh, no thank you, no thank you. 10 is a perfect number.
We should make 20 for Mori. / All right, all right.
Did I forget to say it? 10 is so amazing. / 20 for Mori Calliope. / Sure, yeah, Mori.
Boy, come on.
Okay, let's get into it.
Kiara and Zeta, please give us the start signal, okay?
Okay!
Should we say it in Indonesian?
Okay. Tiga, dua, satu, apa pula?
Okay. Three, two, one, what next?
Okay, I'm ready.
Tiga! Dua! Satu! GO!
Three! Two! One! GO!
1! 2! 3! 4! 5!
Nice squats! Go, go, go! Jump!
Jump!
Oh, they both got it!
Oh, it's so fast!
I know, look how crunchy!
Oh my god, it's going...
Very crunchy.
Speed eating contest!
They can't even talk right now!
もぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ...
Mogu mogu mogu mogu mogu mogu...
Don't choke, though! Don't choke!
Yeah, don't choke. Breathe! Breathe!
Don't choke! Exhale! Inhale!
Mogu mogu... They're inhaling the food.
Okay, they both look pretty much done?
I know! Oh yeah, almost done! The last chewing...
And... Shake that booty!
1! 2! 3! 4! 5!
牛丼屋さん？
Gyudon restaurant?
How now? Gotta get all the way back to the line!
Got it? Did they finish at the same time?!
Photo finish! It seems like a tie.
Hey, quit shaking that ass!
I actually think that I gave you 15, by the way.
No, keep shaking that ass! Keep shaking that ass!
やべえ...
Oh boy...
That seemed like a tie. Good job, good job though.
Okay. It was pretty much a photo finish, but maybe we can check who made it to the finish line first?
Yeah, photo finish. Just like my Umas! Photo finish!
Do you two have an idea who made it first?
I don't know. I feel like it was pretty much the exact same. We just can't be sure.
You were pretty synced up with the mogu mogu also.
I know. That surprised me. I didn't know that it was that hard to eat.
No, it was really dry! Yeah, it was really dry! I didn't know that!
Reine, have you ever eaten, what's it, kerupuk so fast?
No! And then like, usually we eat it with drinks and other food!
There is no water. Yeah.
I got crumbs all over your beautiful tile, I'm sorry.
Oh, yeah! It's okay. No need to clean cause next we're going right where... That's right, yeah.
But for now, I guess we shall give the point to...
Ah! Oh! We got it!
Wait, what?! The results are in! The results are in!
Please announce the time for us.
Okay. Who's first? We got the results!
So... Mori Calliope finished with a time of 55.1 seconds!
And... Not yet, not yet.
And Reine—it was a close one—finished with a time of 55.5 seconds!
That's 0.4 seconds difference! 0.4!
That was really close.
Oh, on my life... That was a great fight.
Good game, good game. Good game.
Oh, rough.
Now, we can take it a bit easy. Yeah, maybe we'll need a drink after this. Let's get a drink.
All right. Is it our turn?
Oh, yes. While we take a break.
Yeah. Now you guys get to eat the super dry snack.
Yay! Good luck! やった！やった！And shake our ass!
Yay! Good luck! Yay! Yay! And shake our ass!
Yeah, that's the part that Kiara is most excited about, of course. If I ever get to it.
All right. Let's get into position.
Okay. Sounds good. See you later.
行くぞ！
Let's go!
VS
Bird versus Cat! Yes!
Wait, which one's the bird and which one's the cat?
I'm the bird. Huh? That's not it. Oh, okay.
I really just doesn't want to be a cat.
She really just doesn't want to be a cat.
Yeah, anything but.
But it's okay, less discussion, more ass-shaking, here we go!
Okay, how are we counting in Indonesian?
Um, tiga, dua, satu, go. Tiga, dua, satu, go.
Um, three, two, one, go. Three, two, one, go.
GO! Ah, not yet, not yet!
Get back there! No cheating!
Remember to squat 5 times! Squat 5 times, okay.
And they need to be good squats. Okay, good squats.
Tiga, dua, satu, go. Okay, got you.
Three, two, one, go. Okay, got you.
Here we go. Tiga! Dua! Satu! GO!
Here we go. Three! Two! One! GO!
1! 2! 3! 4! 5!
That was so low! Come on!
Oh dang, she really went for it. All right, get...
Oh my lord, she's having a hard time. 大丈夫？
Oh my lord, she's having a hard time. Are you okay?
Oh, Kiara...
You got it, Kiara, you've got to try again, you've got to try again! You're eating nothing!
You're eating nothing. 頑張って！
You're eating nothing. Do your best!
Jump, jump, jump! You can just jump, just jump!
幻の...
Phantom...
Can't jump. Just jump.
Aah!
Okay, try, try again. Try again!
Try again! A little higher, a little higher.
You got it, you got it, you got it. Eat, eat, eat!
Eat, eat, eat, eat, eat, come on! Shred on, shred on! Come on, you got this.
Yum, yum. Ooh, yummy. Pretend it's a delicious macaroon. Oh my god, are you okay?
Ooh, yummy. Mmm, delicious macaroon.
がんばれ！You okay?
Do your best! You okay?
Use the saliva! Use the saliva! Just like generate some saliva.
You got this. Just keep... you got this.
Macaroons! Mmm, yummy! So sugary, sweet, delicious macaroons!
It's like... What's her favorite food again?
I'm done!
Macaroons and like... She likes sweets.
Wait, Zeta!?
I ate it as fast as I could!
Kiara, you got this! Kiara, you got this, come on!
Is the video on? You're doing so good.
0.5... Hold on.
Good job, good job.
How many times? Ten times, ten times.
Ten times, okay.
0 to 0.5... I got it, I got it!
Shake that butt! You're good, okay.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten!
Oh my god, shaking that ass!
Oh, I got slowpokes over here!
I've heard that line somewhere before.
I've heard that line too. This butt got you hypnotized.
My favorite clock says that.
Good job! Good job, good job.
Your eating may have been better, but my ass shaking may have been better.
Okay, fine. It was pretty good, it was pretty good.
I was like looking for a main meal, I think so.
Yeah, that thing was going crazy. She was doing circles with it, it was crazy.
I wonder who won?
Yeah, okay, let's announce both of your times too. Okay, let's go center, center.
Alright, let's go, let's go. Let's hear the times, let's hear the times.
Where's the time? We need a time.
Mmm, but they are cooking, they're cooking up the time. They be cooking. Okay, they'll figure it out.
They'll figure it out. Stream, figure it out. Merch will be raining, yay. Yes, definitely don't miss it.
Yeah! Damn, I jumped as high as I could, but... You were really going crazy.
You were doing it with style. Like a superhero.
Yeah, I know! You're flying! Like a superhero.
Thank you, thank you, I tried hard.
But Zeta, the short cat, she just... Cats, they jump really high!
Hind legs.
Oh, we got the time! Oh, right!
Please! Oh boy, okay.
Okay, please! Eeeh!
Wait, really? Yeah, okay. Are we sure this is correct?
That's crazy! Okay, wow. So...
Kiara finished with a time of 1 minute and 42 seconds!
Yay! Woohoo!
Pretty good! Yeah, it is good.
And it looks like Zeta finished with a time of 1 minute 40 seconds!
Oh yeah! Two seconds!
Congratulations! That that's crazy.
So, so, in total... In total?
In total, well, in total, so after the first game...
...with 55.1 was it? I think 1. Yeah, 55.1...
Calli currently has the fastest time!
Calliope! Calliope!
さすが。やったー！
As expected. Yay!
I did it! やったー！
I did it! We did it!
Kiara was so extra, though, with her...
Thank you, thank you, thank you. I get extra points.
That was pretty good, that was awesome.
You really you really you were doing circles with it, it was crazy. I butt. Yeah!
That shake. Yeah! Camera, camera, can you shake it back? Shake it back!
Ah, you can't get that for free. You missed it! You missed it, you're not going to get it!
You can't get that for free. You can't get that for free.
Not for free. Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Damn! Whoa!
Maybe Maybe you can get it for free.
Free! Really sorry Reine, sorry stream.
No, it's alright, it's alright. It's alright, we'll we'll we'll clip that and upload a separate VOD of that too.
Anyways, yeah, I'm so glad it worked out cuz I really wanted you guys to try the kerupuk. I'm sorry it was like dry and stuff.
No, no, no. There's drinks over there, probably.
It was fun, right? Very fun!
It feels like I grew up in Indonesia now. Yay! Indonesian now!
Yeah, it feels like I grew up in Indonesia, too.
It feels like I grew up in Indonesia, too.
Thanks for sharing that part of your childhood with us. Yay! Fun!
Okay, I guess it's time to move on to the next game, maybe?
There's more games? Oh, there's more games? More games.
Yeah, but before that, before we continue...
...I would like everyone to watch a little bit of the footage from my Japan location shoot!
Ooh, there's gonna be more food! So, here we go!
Here we go! Yay!
Hey, so did anyone get jealous watching me enjoy my delicious meal in Indonesia earlier?
Well, don't worry, cuz you can eat ID food right here in Tokyo too!
I'm at an Indonesian restaurant in Roppongi, Tokyo today.
The restaurant is called Wayang Bali,
and it's a lovely place where you can enjoy a wide variety of delicious Indonesian cuisine.
But, I want to share my food with someone.
So, let's introduce these dishes to a very special JP member!
Yay! Haachama-chama! Worldwide-traveling idol, Akai Haato!
Yay!
Thank you so much, Haachama, for coming!
Thank you, too!
Yay, let's head inside and see what delicious dishes they have today!
Yay, let's go! I'm so excited!
Phew!
I'm hungry!
Hungry! I'm excited!
Yay! So, I have invited you out to eat with me to celebrate my birthday this year!
Yay! Happy birthday!
Thank you for coming!
Nice!
So, like, for this year, I wanted to try something new and celebrate my Indonesian culture by sharing it with everyone.
Yay!
We ate instant noodles together before, right?
So, that's why I wanted you to try...
some real Indonesian food this time!
Yeah! So you can level up, you can level up your Indonesian!
Next time, I go to Indonesia!
Yes!
There's also spicy food here,
but I think they won't be as spicy as the spicy noodles.
So you don't have to worry.
Yeah.
But you're excited about spicy, right?
I want spicy!
Pedan, pedan! Uh?
Pedas.
Pedas, pedas!
Haachama, pedas lover.
Pedas lover. I love pedas!
Me too, I love pedas.
How do you say "I love pedas" in Indonesian?
Aku suka...
pedas.
Aku suka pedas!
Yeah! That means, "I love spicy."
Yay!
See, I'm slowly turning Haachama Indonesian by feeding her Indonesian food!
Yeah, you did it!
Yay!
Oh~ So this is the menu~
Oh, it's also written here, Indonesian food vocabulary.
So if you want to learn Indonesian, there's so many words here.
辛い、PEDAS。
Spicy is "PEDAS".
Pedas! Yeah!
はあちゃまPEDAS好きでしょ？ / PEDAS好き！
Haachama, you like spicy, right? / I like spicy!
これは... ada kukus, bakar...
This has... "kukus" (steamed), "bakar" (grilled)...
Bakar. Bakar, bakar!
「R」が付いてるよ。Bakar is 焼く。
There's an "R" roll. "Bakar" means grilled.
Yes. 炒めるはtumis。
Yes. Stir-fried is "tumis".
Yeah.
Indonesian already! インドネシア語教室が始まるよ〜
Indonesian already! Indonesian class is starting~
Satay~
Do you know sate?
ああ、焼き...つくし...串焼き！
Ah, grilled... skewers... grilled skewers!
Yes!
インドネシアの串焼きですね。
They're Indonesian grilled skewers.
Do you know what tempe is?
Tempe? Tempe? Tempe? 分からないや。
Tempe? Tempe? Tempe? I don't know.
So, tempe is like... apa ya... so in Indonesia, it's kind of like the primary source of protein.
So, tempe is like... in Indonesia, it's kind of like the primary source of protein.
Protein? / Yes. / Wow!
And then, I think they kinda use the same base materials as natto.
Natto? / Yeah.
So they're like cousins! I mean... yeah!
Protein natto!
Yeah. Do you like natto?
Ah, I like natto.
Oh really? I haven't... / Can you eat it?
I've tried, but I don't know if I like it.
How to, how to ini, how to like natto?
How to, how to... how to like natto?
まぜまぜ、まぜまぜ。 / Maze-maze. Okay, okay. / Mix!
Mix-mix, mix-mix. / Mix-mix. Okay, okay. / Mix!
So if you like natto, then maybe you will like tempe!
Oh, yay, tempe!
There's also, this is also spicy: dabu-dabu.
Dabu-dabu! I like the name!
Fried chicken with, yeah, dabu-dabu is the sauce name, and there's also spicy chicken: ayam pedas.
Well, anyway, we went through a lot of the menu, so I guess we should order a bunch, and we can try them all!
But, we should also give you... Since you're turning Indonesian, we need to give you an Indonesian introduction!
Oh, yeah! Good idea!
So, can you say your introduction, just in your normal, yeah?
Haachama-chama~! Worldwide-traveling idol, Akai Haato!
Okay, okay. So, in Indonesian, that would be:
Haachama-chama~
Idola...
yang... / Idola yang...
menjelajahi... / 何が？
menjelajahi... / What was that?
One more time! Menjelajahi...
Menjelajahi. / Menjelajahi.
Menjelajahi. / Menjelajahi. / dunia...
dunia... Akai Haato!
Menjelajahi dunia Akai Haato. 最初の言葉はなんだっけ？
Menjelajahi dunia Akai Haato. What was the first word?
Idola... / Idola...
yang... / Idola yang...
menjelajahi...
dunia... / dunia...
Idola yang menjelajahi...
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
Ah, Samba!
Yeah, spicy, spicy. So basically...
...fresh, raw, zesty. So it's kind of like...
...sour and spicy and...
...it's finely sliced and then you pour hot oil on it.
Ooh...
Ooh, so this looks delicious. Let us try.
Oh, is it meat?
Yes, it's chicken meat.
Oh, it's chicken meat.
Ini tulang muda, my favorite.
This is soft bone, my favorite.
Mmm, ah! I had taste before.
Mmm, ah! I've tasted this before.
Really?
Uh, it's like the Indonesian noodle.
It's like Indonesian noodles.
Pop Mie Ayam Bawang? I taste something like that, really?
Pop Mie Chicken Onion? I taste something like that, really?
This is nankotsu, my favorite.
This is soft bone cartilage, my favorite.
Oh!
We were supposed to comment on the dishes,
but it's too delicious so all I can do is eat.
What's a girl gotta do?
Nankotsu, I'll I'll try nankotsu. Where is the nankotsu?
Cartilage, I'll try the cartilage. Where is the cartilage?
Nankotsu... ah, this one. Not this one.
Cartilage... Ah, this one. Not this one.
This one. Not this one. This one.
Nankotsu.
Cartilage.
I'm gonna try more of the sambal, yeah? Onion?
Samba, samba.
Oh, what's this? Oh, there's also shallots, fried onion.
Oh, what's this? Oh, there's also shallots, fried onions.
Mmm, it tastes like mie goreng.
Mmm.
Ah, it's sour now.
Yeah, you can really taste the sour.
Mmm, but it's not spicy.
Salty, right? Salty and crunchy.
It's salty, yeah.
Yeah, so there are many, many sambal types in Indonesia,
and this is one of them.
When you get the chance, you should try more sambal.
Yay! Sate ga kichaimashita! Yay! Sate!
Yay! The satay has arrived! Satay!
So, kore wa desu ne, sate campur.
So this is, like I said earlier, mixed satay.
Terus ini ayam. This is chicken.
And then this is chicken. This is chicken.
Chicken.
Ini beef. Beef.
This is beef. Beef.
Ini lamb. Lamb.
This is lamb. Lamb.
Ebi. Ebi, shrimp.
Shrimp. Shrimp, shrimp.
Spicy chicken. Spicy chicken!
Yeah, you want spicy, right? Yeah.
Can I just eat this now?
Okay, so this is like peanut sauce. It's so friggin' good, yeah.
Peanut sauce? Really? Oh, I haven't eat with peanut sauce.
Peanut sauce? Really? Oh, I haven't eaten it with peanut sauce.
You want chicken? Yeah.
Oh, thank you.
Let's eat the chicken first. Eat it.
We ate so many chicken today!
I know. Yeah, chicken is very common in Indonesian food, I guess, right?
Mmm, creamy.
And sometimes, aside from peanut sauce, they also put like sweet soy sauce.
Mmm. It's same chicken, but it's really different taste.
Mmm. It's the same chicken, but it's a really different taste.
Yeah, different seasoning, right?
Which one you wanna try next?
Which one do you wanna try next?
This one. Beef? Okay.
Beef, oh, with peanut sauce? Ooh!
Yeah, so normally the one that the people eat the most is chicken.
Yeah, this is like beef or lamb, maybe it's a little bit uncommon, yeah, but delicious.
Delicious. Yum yum yum. Everything peanut sauce.
Mmm, the beef is delicious. I like it.
I want to try ebi. Do you want to try ebi?
I want to try shrimp. Do you want to try shrimp?
Ebi! I like! I like ebi!
Shrimp! I like! I like shrimp!
Ebi is not peanut sauce, I think.
Shrimp is not peanut sauce, I think.
You eat this one?
Ah, I think... I don't know.
Mmm, itadakimasu.
Mmm, bon appétit.
I like this one.
I like this one too!
Mmm. Ebi, ebi but not normal ebi.
Mmm. Shrimp, shrimp, but not normal shrimp.
The seasoning is so good, it's a different seasoning.
Um, it's not peanut sauce like the others, but it's so good.
Okay, which one's next? Let's go lamb. Okay, lamb, let's go.
Oh, there's a... onions?
Bye bye, onions! Bye bye, onions! Let's go.
Bye-bye, onions! Bye-bye, onions! Let's go.
So the lamb is does not have, in not in peanut sauce, yeah.
So the lamb does not have, not in peanut sauce, yeah.
Mmm, okay. What seasoning is this?
It's not peanut sauce, but like it's some kind of like sweet...
Sweet sauce. Sweet a bit. Mhm, mmm.
Let's go spicy, let's go spicy! Wait, I drink.
Let's go spicy, let's go spicy! Wait, I'll drink.
Padam... Pa- Pade- Padam, Padim... Pedas.
Pedas!
Ooh, let's see. Is it How spicy is it?
Ooh, let's see. How spicy is it?
Kind of like sweet, spicy.
Yeah, I see it, like it's slowly like... Mmm.
Ah, it's slowly coming. Yeah, it's slowly coming, yeah?
It's really good, I like it.
Ah, spicy!
Yeah. I don't know what kind of seasoning this is, this is so good.
So, which one is your favorite out of this one?
So, which one is your favorite out of these ones?
I really like the shrimp. Ooh.
My favorite one is the beef.
It's ju- I think it's just because I never really...
I think it's just because I never really...
...eat beef satay that much before,
and this is so... heavy.
and this is so... / ...heavy.
We have Mie Goreng!
Yeah, I'm crying!
No!
So I guess that's why they didn't give us like rice.
So I guess that's why they didn't give us rice.
That was really spicy!
It's okay, this is not spicy.
Yeah. Mmm.
This is Mie Goreng.
Mie Goreng! Mie Goreng!
Yeah, so you ate the instant Mie Goreng already?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
This is the not instant version.
I'm so happy this is not spicy.
Happy, happy!
I like the spicy, but...
I like spicy food, but...
...I'm happy we get to rest.
Not now.
Ah, it's もちもち！
Ah, it's nice and chewy!
Mmm.
Ah, it's the 太麺。
Ah, they're thick noodles.
Yeah, the texture of the noodles is...
...mmm, very enyal-enyal.
...mmm, very chewy.
何それ？
What's that?
Enyal-enyal is Indonesian for もちもち。
Enyal-enyal is Indonesian for "chewy".
Ah, it's cute!
Enyal-enyal.
あにょあにょ！あにょあにょ！
Anya-anya! Anya-anya!
It's あにょあにょ〜
It's anya-anya~
Everyone has different Mie Gorengs at home,
but this style, I really like this style.
So many, many toppings.
So many toppings.
It's... it's like 焼きそば！
It's... it's like yakisoba!
Mmm, it is Indonesian yakisoba.
Yakisoba but, uh, sweet.
Yakisoba, but sweet.
Sweet than yakisoba.
Sweeter than yakisoba.
So earlier we have...
So earlier we had...
...natto cousin, now we have yakisoba cousin.
...natto's cousin, now we have yakisoba's cousin.
Yakisoba cousin!
And finally, this is Bali's traditional dish...
...called Lawar.
Lawar! Lawar! Lawar!
I've actually never had this before.
Really?
Yeah, so this will be my first time also.
Yeah, so this will be my first time too.
Yay!
I'm so excited.
So in this dish we have some peanuts...
Pean- Oh, it's peanuts!
Yeah, this one is peanuts.
I thought natto! It's not.
I thought it was natto! It's not.
And then we have some...
インゲン？
Green beans?
インゲン。So, インゲン英語で何て言うの？
Green beans. So, how do you say "ingen" in English?
う〜ん...私もわかんない。
Umm... I don't know either.
Green... Green what...
Green... ah, buncis.
Green... ah, green beans.
Buncis.
Green beans.
Yeah. And then...
So normally this is served with 豚肉...
So normally this is served with pork...
...well, they usually serve it with pork,
but because this edition is like halal edition,
but because this is halal,
so they replace it with 鶏肉...
they replaced it with chicken...
鶏肉。Yeah, with chicken.
Chicken. Yeah, with chicken.
Chicken. Mhm.
Yummy! I'm so excited.
I wonder how this tastes like, cuz there's also like shallots and everything.
I wonder what this tastes like, because there's also shallots and everything.
Let's try it!
Tunggu, I'll try the buncis first.
Wait, I'll try the green beans first.
インゲン。いただきます！
Green beans. Bon appétit!
Kasih masuk.
Dig in.
Mmm, I like... The インゲン is very crunchy, mmm.
Mmm, I like... The green beans are very crunchy, mmm.
Oh, it's like a snack!
It is kind of like a snack. Actually, wait, it is like a snack.
Yeah. And it's salty, also.
Yeah. And it's salty, too.
I wanna eat for おやつ。
I'd want to eat this as a snack.
Yeah, yeah.
It's yummy!
Mmm, good.
Mmm, we've eaten so many things!
Yeah!
Is your stomach okay?
Yeah, okay.
Is there room? More room? 'Cause you know... you know what comes after these meals?
Is there room? More room? Because you know what comes after these meals?
For dessert?
Yes!
Okay, it's time for dessert!
What do we have? Yay!
And what do we have here? We have mango pudding!
Look at these layers! It's so good.
Ooh. What is this, like chocolate?
I'm not sure, or like...
Salt? Sugar?
Ah, let's taste it.
Yeah. Let's taste it to be sure.
Ooh. Wah! It's pudding!
Yeah.
Ooh!
It's so soft.
Okay, wait. I'll try, I'll try.
Okay.
Mmm, it's so creamy!
And the mango... Oh, the mango! ...flavor is so good, yeah!
And the mango flavor is so good, yeah!
Like, I have no idea, but like this is so creamy and maybe there's like a hint of coconut milk, maybe?
I have no idea, but this is so creamy, and maybe there's a hint of coconut milk?
But I'm not sure.
I'm not sure though.
Ah, it's creamy.
It is, it is.
Wait, what's down here?
What is the brown...
I'm curious about the brown stuff.
I'll I'll get the brown one.
I'll get the brown one.
Ahhh...
Like caramelized, ah...
Oh, this one, this one!
Yeah, yeah, that one.
Wah!
It's caramel!
Mmm, also like the burnt caramelized...
Mmm, also like burnt caramelized...
Ah. ...flan? Yeah.
Mmm.
Wait, this is so good, guys.
That's nice.
And then we have more, apparently! Oh, my god.
Ooh!
This is fried banana snack.
Fried banana!
Sounds yummy!
Yeah.
So fried banana is like...
...it's literally banana and then you have batter and then you deep fry it.
...it's literally banana in batter, and then you deep fry it.
It must be good.
Yeah.
It's a very famous...
It's a very famous snack in Indonesia.
Oh.
We don't always eat it with ice cream,
but it's fancy, I guess. I'm not complaining.
Oh, smells good! Smells good!
Mmm, yeah.
うー！熱っ！
Ooh! Ow, hot!
熱っ、熱っ...
It's hot, so hot...
熱っ...
It's so hot...
美味い！
It's good!
バターが... I think the batter is delicious.
The batter... I think the batter is delicious.
It's the best! It's the best!
Yes, this is very good.
It's sweet, but not too sweet.
アップルパイっぽい感じ
Like an apple pie.
Mmm, yeah, yeah, kind of like that. I like it.
Camera roll is gonna be just full of us eating this and saying nothing.
The camera roll is going to be just full of us eating this and saying nothing.
Okay. Yay~!
完食
[Finished]
Thank you so much for coming today, Haachama!
Thank you so much for inviting me!
Was it good?
So fun! Yeah! I had fun, too. Thank you!
Now that you tried so much Indonesian food,
次は, what do we do so we level you up more?
next, what do we do so we level you up more?
I'll go to Indonesia! Yeah!
Yes! And now I like Indonesian food now.
Indonesian food, next you go holiday in Indonesia.
Indonesian food, next you go on holiday to Indonesia.
I'll make it, I'll cook!
Oh, yeah! I'll cook! Haachama cooking Indonesian dishes! Let's do it!
And also, also, also, take me to eat some underrated Japanese food, too.
Yeah, I want to know what Japanese people eat.
I'll teach you!
Yes, day-to-day Japanese people food. Yummy!
So everyone, look forward to more Haachama and Reine adventures, all right?
Yay! Let's go back to the studio!
Studio Reine, are you there?
スタジオのレイネさ～ん、取れますかぁ～？
Studio Reine, can you hear us?
はーい！スタジオのレイネでーす！
Yes! It's Reine in the studio!
So, what did you think of our trip to the Indonesian restaurant in Japan with Haachama?
Looks so delicious! What a meal! I want to go!
I'll take you guys there next time!
Please! Food, food, food, food! I'm getting hungry.
All right, next up, let's play our second game!
Yay! Okay.
Well, just like in game one, we will be competing to see who can reach the goal the fastest.
Yeah!
Okay, are you guys ready? No. Yeah!
For this game, we will be using this item!
Okay. Oh, wow, beach balls! Ooh! Yay!
Man, I wish I was a baller. Wish I was a little bit taller.
I wish I had a '64 Impala.
If I had a girl who looked cute, I would call her.
Whoa, the violence! This is... I'm cooling the camera.
Hey, this isn't soccer, all right? You knock that off. World Cup is over.
Okay, okay, okay. The rules for the next game is super simple.
You hold this ball between your legs like you're giving birth, so...
Eh anjir... yang bener neng...
Whoa damn... be serious, miss...
Yeah, so like this...
And then you guys will be racing while hopping.
Aw, I thought we were going to play football! No, you're not!
Next time, next year, football, let's go.
Okay, okay. Let's go, let's go. Football gak kuku, let's go.
Okay, okay. Let's go, let's go. Football is irresistible, let's go.
And the game is called... the Bola Challenge!
Bola means ball. Bola Challenge.
Bola. Ballin'. Ballin'~ Ballin'. Look at the biggest ball!
Mine's definitely small just because skirt situation. So tiny.
Mine's definitely small just because of the skirt situation. So tiny.
Oh, sure, that's why. Yeah, well, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, small ball. Hey, hey, stop.
Okay, so basically, all you have to do is hold the ball and then...
...you start there and hop to the turnaround point, and then make it to the finish line, right?
Simple, right? Yeah. That's simple. Very simple.
Yeah, okay. Well, there's a twist, actually.
To make things more interesting, we're adding two extra rules.
Okay.
First, you'll be given a topic, and you have to race while talking about it.
Oh~!
Yeah, so it's just like, you know, you guys are good at yapping, right? It's just like...
I guess so. Yeah, now you can do that while jumping.
I never I never tried yapping while balling, okay, okay. Yeah, yeah.
Never too late to pick up a new skill. Yeah.
Put it in your resume. Yeah.
Put it on your resume. Yeah.
Yeah, and just like before, two people will compete at a time, so make sure...
...you keep chatting with your partner while you race. Opponent partner, mm-mm-mm, right?
All right, the yapping has to...
Are you okay? Are you okay? Yeah.
I tried doing a trick. I'm sorry. Go on.
Okay, and the second rule is after you pass that point, you can try to mess with your opponent.
So if you want to tickle your opponent, if you want to, yeah...
Yeah, exactly. Stop!
Hey, I'm not going to do that to you.
Yeah, basically like that. I mean, well, yeah...
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
Anyway... / Not yet!
Not yet?
After this race, you'll get to know each other now.
All righty. Well then, it looks like I'm going to be tanto for this match.
Ayo.
So, here is your topic.
Okay?
Compliment each other in Japanese!
えぇー？！
Eh?!
No English, no Indonesian allowed.
This is a good challenge for somebody, or two people who speak three languages.
Oh damn.
Well Kiara also speaks three languages.
Hey!
So you'll have no excuse.
Compliment each other in German.
German?!
Now there's a real challenge.
Guten Morgen. / Guten Morgen.
Good morning. / Good morning.
Dankeschön, dankeschön, dankeschön...
Thank you very much, thank you very much...
That's not even a compliment.
Okay! Are you ready?
Yeah.
And on your marks, get set, go!
Go!
絶対可愛い！ / 可愛い！
You're definitely cute! / Cute!
足長い！ / 綺麗！
Long legs! / Pretty!
頑張れ！ / 可愛い！
Do your best! / Cute!
デート行かない？
Wanna go on a date?
行こう！
Let's go!
行こう！絶対可愛い！チュチュチュ！
Let's go! Definitely cute! Mwah mwah mwah!
イエーイ！
Yay!
Wait, wait, did they compliment each other? I didn't hear.
I think so. I'm pretty sure I heard some compliments.
It was a little hard to say—to hear what they were saying, but they were definitely complimenting each other.
What were you saying to each other?
Um, I was saying "zettai kawaii", "ashi nagai", and then "your hair is pretty"...
Um, I was saying "definitely cute", "long legs", and then "your hair is pretty"...
...and then "let's go on a date sometime", and then I did the "chu chu chu".
Those are compliments.
Yeah, that are—those are compliments.
What did you say to her?
I said, "Wow, 君は素晴らしい！"
I said, "Wow, you are wonderful!"
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
拳強い！
Strong fists!
足強い, that's good.
Strong legs, that's good.
Bonjour.
そして...
And then...
Yeah, those are compliments.
That was successful then. Good job, team.
And we got the times ready, maybe, too.
Good job! Let's check out the times.
Yeah, let's see, let's see.
So do you both know each other now?
Yes!
Let's meet!
You guys are sweating each other—sweating away.
All righty, fine, fine.
Hey, I want my ball—my ball should hang out with you guys, too.
Oh, wow!
We only just met, but it's kind of fun.
I don't know.
No way.
Do we have the times? Let's check them out. We probably have them now.
I think I could tell who won, though.
Ah, got it. Saw it.
It was close!
It was definitely closer than ours.
Just like earlier, it was close.
Okay, we got it. The times, do you want to say them?
Sure thing.
Okidoki. Now, Reine, your time was...
12 seconds!
Woohoo!
And Zeta...
Sorry...
大丈夫？ / 大丈夫、大丈夫。
Are you okay? / It's okay, it's okay.
These balls be wildin'.
Zeta, your time was... 14 seconds!
Woah!
Good job. Any number with the number four included is a good number.
It's a good number, so...
The winner of your match was...
Reine!
Best of the bunch!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Good job!
How do you feel?
Hmm, yeah, I feel great.
Energized? Ready for more exercise?
Yeah! Bring it on!
This is rigged. She's the birthday girl, of course she would win.
Well, everyone had to win.
Everyone, you all did an amazing job.
Oh, thank you! / Thank you! It was fun.
We finished both games, so we're gonna total up everyone's times and announce the winner!
Yes, the person with the shortest total time!
大丈夫？ / Are you okay?
Are you okay? / Are you okay?
It's hot here in Indonesia, that is why!
Take a breath, take a breath while I—
CPR! CPR! CPR, everyone! Ahhh!
Kiara, you do it.
What?!
Do you do it? You do the CPR.
I'm dying, somebody CPR please!
Kiara will do it.
Where?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's fine.
やばい！やばい、大丈夫！大丈夫！
Oh no! Oh no, I'm okay! I'm okay!
事故、事故。
Accident, accident.
That what you wanted?
She lives!
Good job. / I'm alive!
お疲れ〜
Good work~
I'm alive. Thank God.
お疲れ, you're alive. Congrats on being alive.
Good work, you're alive. Congrats on being alive.
Do we have the results yet?
Wait, wait, while we're waiting on the results...
Oh.
Here's my sick trick.
Okay, do it. / Calli, catch.
Okay, I'm ready.
Are you ready to catch? / Yeah.
Well, it was a little low.
I don't know what happened. It was a little low.
All right, one more time, one more time.
I'm ready, I'm ready. / Let's get it again.
Here you go. Three, two, one!
Woah! Nice!
Let's go, Takamori! Takamori! Takamori ball masters!
Takamori ball masters! / Ball masters!
Takamori knows ball!
Woah, we're balling!
Yeah, good job.
That was awesome, that was a sick trick.
Well, we should become like a football club.
For sure, yeah.
The team.
Oh, results are in! We got it!
We got it, you guys all got it.
The results are in, and let's announce the winner, okay?
And let's start with the fourth place. Drumroll, please!
Takanashi Kiara!
Four is the best number!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Last place, but I mean, first place in...
in your hearts, right?
Yeah! So true!
Fourth place is first from the bottom.
ああ、すごい！ So true!
Ah, amazing! So true!
I'm so すごい！
I'm so amazing!
Also number one ball knower.
Number one baller.
You see how well she knows that ball?
You see it?
Woah! Woah!
Okay, and then the third place is our very own beloved house cat...
Vestia Zeta!
Beloved house... secret agent.
Well, I didn't get last place! Yay!
Okay, hand, please. Hand, please.
Damn it, so cute.
Okay, good girl! Congratulations!
That's more of a dog thing, though. Yeah.
Cat, dog, same thing, same thing.
Not the same animal. Not the same animal.
It's kind of adjacent, whatever.
Okay, and in second place, just missing out on the win, it's...
Pavolia Reine!
Birthday girl! I know her!
Yay!
Thank you! (blows kiss)
Wait, Calli, you didn't give her the win on her birthday?
Should I... Wait, what? Should I have done that? Was that... is that like... a manners thing?
Oh god! Sorry, sorry!
No, no, no, no, I prepared something for the winner, so that's okay!
And that means our champion, with the fastest time, Mr. Ball, Mori Calliope!
Mr. Ball, please don't hurt me! Ah, please don't hurt me! Ah!
Congratulations!
Thank you! Thank you, oh my gosh! I appreciate it. I have been training.
So, Mori, who got the fastest time, has earned a very special trophy!
Thank you!
Ta-da-da-da-da-da-da!
Oh, trophy. Can I pass my ball to you? Yeah!
This is a very special trophy for today!
Woah, I won! Yay!
Thank you! Thank you so much! Thank you!
Anyways, any comments? Any, you know, interview? Winner interview?
Um, this was really fun! I had such a great time enjoying Indonesia!
But more than anything, I'm glad we all got to have lots of fun on your very special day. Reine, thank you for inviting us...
Thank you!
and sharing with us some of the games that, you know, you used to like to play and stuff like that. It's just a really good time. So thank you!
No, thank you so much, Calli! And thank you, Wawa and Zeta, for participating!
And that's all for the games! Thank you so much for playing with me, everyone!
Yay! Thank you! Thank you!
And coming up at the end of the stream, I have a very, very special surprise...
a brand new song performance!
Woah! New song! New song! New song! New song! Yay! New song!
But before we get there, I want to show you...
the teaser video for the new song and introduce some merch!
Ooh, merch!
So don't go anywhere, and stay with us until the very end! We will!
Yay! Alright, now let's take a look at the teaser video for the new song! Weee!
どうぞ！ Please!
Go ahead! Please!
今 何処へでも 駆け抜けて
Now, run through toward anywhere!
[Pavolia Reine New Original Song / Endless Blue / 2026.09.09 24:00 RELEASE]
Hehe, how did you like the teaser video?
Yeah! Yeah! What are they doing?
You guys are so suspicious!
So, well, this new song is, you know my very first original song, "Gate Open: START!"? Yes! Yeah!
So if "Gate Open: START!" is the opening of an anime, this is kind of, you know, a little bit more mellow vibe, maybe like a second season opening of Gate Open: START!
I love that! Yeah! いいね！
I love that! Yeah! Nice!
Reine anime when? Let's go!
I'd watch it! Second season おめでとう！ おめでとう！ おめでとう！
I'd watch it! Second season congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations!
Well, as I mentioned earlier, I'll be performing it later, so please look forward to it! Yay!
And now, before I perform the new song, I'd like to have my guests here, my beautiful, beautiful guests, help me introduce this year's birthday merch!
Alright everyone, get over here!
We won't let you down! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy!
Yeah, get out your wallet! Buy now! Ta-da!
Okay, first up, "Take me with U Acrylic Diorama Stand" featuring a beautiful illustration by Enji-sensei of me enjoying mie ayam with a beautiful view! Whenever you go to a restaurant, please take me with you! Yay!
What are you guys doing? Get your oshikatsu pictures.
Yeah! Oshikatsu! Don't forget oshikatsu! Oshikatsu!
Next! Next! Next!
Oi, oi, Kiara, you're up!
Wait, do we have a part in this?
Yes! You have a job to do!
I will introduce the second item: the Travel Towel!
Towel!
Don't let the name fool you, this is a super versatile towel...
...that you can use not only for traveling, but also in your everyday life!
Wipe your armpits, wipe your armpits!
It sure will come in handy at the next fes too, for example!
Towel! Towel! Towel! Towel! Towel! Towel! Towel! Towel!
And next!
次、次、次...
Next, next, next...
And the third item is... Ta-da! Mie Ayam Bowl!
Yay!
Ayam! Mie ayam! 美味しい、美味しい！
Ayam! Mie ayam! Delicious, delicious!
As the name suggests, this bowl is perfect for eating mie ayam...
...but it's also great for ramen, soup, and all kinds of other dishes!
So, I'm sure you'll get lots of use for it. You can use it for anything!
Anything!
You can even put cat food into it!
Yeah!
You can even use it as a hat!
Whatever works!
Yeah, I hope this bowl helps you enjoy lots of tasty meals!
Tasty! Nom nom nom...
Very nice! And last but certainly not least, the fourth item—
Just kidding, it's not last, but I was assigned number four because I am a shinigami—
The fourth item is... the Lovely travel partner Plushie Keychain!
Yay!
It is the perfect size to bring on all your trips and your adventures.
Take this adorable little Reine in her costume with you wherever you go and have lots of fun together!
Yay! 素晴らしい！
Yay! Wonderful!
Yay! And this time, I also have a special situational voice...
...'Spooky travel partner'!
It includes scary stories recorded in three languages!
Hey, great! Yes, multilingual is so scary!
English, Indonesian—no mixed voice this time, sorry, no mixed language voice.
And of course, the full set comes with an exclusive postcard bonus!
Don't miss out!
We also have a limited number of postcards with my handwritten signature, so make sure you don't miss out on this chance!
I want Reine's autograph!
Yeah! I want Reine's autograph!
Hey no, me, me first! I'm gonna buy real fast! Ooh, gotta hustle!
Can you beat Mori Calliope's speed?
Definitely not!
All right, I'll see you guys in the pit, let's go. Fighting for Reine's signature, all you guys better be ready.
Didn't we already fight enough?
Well, I want to fight the fans now.
Yeah, it's their turn now! All right, next!
And that wraps up our merch intro...duction!
Okay, move, back, back, back, back!
Back back back... Back where? I forgot where I was!
I don't know where I was!
Here, maybe here I think.
Okay guys, whew! This year's birthday celebration was so much fun!
I got to go to two different location shoots, spend time with everyone, and make so many great memories.
So thank you, thank you so much again for making my birthday a blast!
You're welcome! Hug! Group hug! Bring it in!
Thank you!
Reine is one year older.
I'm one year older!
Congrats on getting closer to me.
Your hair is turning gray.
Yours is, too!
マジですか？
Really?
And now, before we know it, we've reached the final part of this stream, and it is time for the new song performance!
Woah!
Wait, hold on, I gotta show you something! I'm gonna get something!
What are you going to get? I'm going to get... Where is she going?
Is that what I think it is?
My beautiful beautiful baby!
Woah!
I'm back! Yay!
It's the Reine bass! Love the stickers!
Do you guys recognize these stickers? Yeah!
All right, I worked really really hard on this song, so I hope you all can enjoy it!
All right, can everyone say the title of the new song together with me?
Okay, let's go!
せーの！ Endless Blue!
One, two! Endless Blue!
Endless Blue
作詞：藤原優樹 作曲・編曲：長谷川大介
Lyrics: Yuki Fujiwara | Music & Arr.: Daisuke Hasegawa
飾り付けた 言葉でなんで
Why did I hide my true heartbeat
本当の鼓動 隠してたんだ
behind dressed-up words?
折りたたんだ羽は
My folded wings
見えない空に焦がれてた
were yearning for a sky out of sight.
パズルなら壊してしまった
If it was a puzzle, I ended up breaking it,
散らばる欠片 バラバラ
its scattered pieces falling apart.
誰かに似た色じゃ
Colors that resemble someone else
意味がない わかってるから
are meaningless, and I know that now.
旅立ちは あの青空のせいだ
Blame this departure on that blue sky,
誤魔化せない 憧れに気づいたから
because I realized a yearning I could no longer deceive.
どうしようもない 衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
動き出した ストーリーの先には
ahead of this story that has begun to move,
不安も 物思いさえも 染めていく
it stains even my anxieties and pensive thoughts.
想像より今 眩い空が 広がってるはずでしょう
A sky more dazzling than imagined must be spreading out right now, isn't it?
扉 開け行こう
So let's open the door and go!
ヤミヤミ 沈む昨日も
The gloomy yesterdays that sank into darkness,
涙見 叫び痛む今日も
and the painful todays filled with tears and screams...
今更なんて言って
Saying "it's too late now,"
願いの色は 燻んでた
the colors of my wishes had grown smoldering and dim.
痛みなら 飲み干してしまおう
If it's pain, I'll swallow it whole;
また乗り越えてみせるよ
I'll overcome it once again.
私でいることに
The weakness of hesitating
ためらう弱さは もういらない
to just be myself—I don't need it anymore.
広げた羽は 飾りじゃないよ
These spread wings aren't just for decoration;
鮮やかな夢を纏おう
let's wrap ourselves in vivid dreams.
その覚悟が ここにあるから
Because that resolve is right here!
幻想の夜 重ねて
Piling up illusory nights,
ふらり 漂うように 歩いていたよ
I was wandering aimlessly, drifting along.
途方もなく遠くて 挫けそうになっても
Even if it seemed endlessly far and I felt like breaking down,
この声は 羽ばたける
this voice of mine
その時を待っていたんだ
was waiting for the moment to take flight.
もう一度 叫んでみるよ
I'll try crying it out once more!
終わりなんてない 旅を続けたくて
Wanting to continue this endless journey,
進んでいく ストーリーの向こうへと
beyond the story moving steadily forward,
この声で 果てない空を渡っていく
with this voice, I will cross the boundless sky.
まだ知らない 遥かな青に 胸を膨らませて
My heart swelling with excitement for the distant blue yet unknown,
無限の明日が きっと待ってるから
because a boundless tomorrow is surely waiting for me,
扉 開け行こう
let's open the door and go!